the first point we need to consider is
for store instructions when does the
memory right actually happen and it
happens at commit we have to do rights
to memory at commit because it is unsafe
to update memory at any point before the
instruction commits an instruction that
has not yet committed is subject to
being canceled for example because of a
branch misprediction or exception so
doing a memory right prematurely might
mean that later we have to undo accesses
to memory meaning we have to kind of put
back the old value of a memory location
which is extremely difficult to do so
what we will do is we will delay memory
rights and stores until commit but does
it mean that the load has to also wait
until commit before it can get data
because only then the data is in memory
so the question is if we write values on
stores that commit where does the load
get data and we want our loads to get
data as early as possible so that we can
finish those loads and supply that data
to the subsequent instructions that
depend on the load for this purpose we
introduce a structure called load/store
queue and that is where we will keep all
loads and stores and we will next see
how loads get data from the stores